[Music]
i designed this low poly lagoon as an
entry level for our game beans or bones
and today i'd like to share with you the
thought process behind designing and
creating this lagoon in a low poly style
the process starts with the story of the
game followed by some research
and based on that i developed some ideas
which i finally implemented now the
story of the game is the following it's
a pirate game and you are stranded on a
cannibal island but instead of cooking
you directly the cannibals offer you a
deal if you help them become vegetarians
you are free to go and beans are bones
is a two player online game so i asked
myself where did cannibals live
and one area i found was papua new
guinea i did an image search on papua
new guinea and found a lot of beautiful
pictures there was one image that
especially caught my attention and which
became the basis for my lagoon i really
love the curves everything's smooth and
everything's overgrown but i still
required some ideas for my village and
the rest of the island so this is the
second image that caught my attention
you have the water and the beach then
you have the village
and around this village you have the
small area of palm trees which is very
distinct from the highly dense
rainforest in the back so let's hop over
into unity and see how i implemented
these core ideas now this is how the
lagoon looks like in the edit and you
directly see some of the core elements
the rounded rocks and
and everything's overgrown
so when i turn the camera you see the
beach with a small village then the area
with the palm trees and behind that the
jungle or rainforest
so how did i implement the scene the
terrain is a standard unity terrain that
i created using gaia pro and in addition
i'm using the micro splat terrain shader
for the water i'm using the crest ocean
shader and i tuned the material to fit
to the stylized or low poly look and
mainly i removed all the reflection from
the water
for vegetation placement and rendering
i'm using vegetation studio pro which is
very flexible and allows for fast
iterations for instance i can create
biomass which is very helpful in placing
all the vegetation so i have a biome for
the beach
for the palm trees and the jungle the
palm trees and most of the rainforest
vegetation comes from the cindy polygon
pirate pack for the rainforest i used
this very low poly and blocky canopies
to get the high density look and feel
with acceptable performance and for the
grass and bushes i'm using the stylized
grass shader which also allows for a
high density with acceptable performance
in this level you can't simply enter the
rainforest so i added some fog as a
visible barrier and for the fork i'm
using the volumetric fog and mist 2
package the towers and the building are
also part of the cinti pirate pack and
finally for the skies i'm using enviro
and i've tuned the clouds so that they
have this stylized look and if you would
like to have a closer look at the level
it's part of the demo that's already
available on steam so hopefully you got
some inspiration for your own level and
if you like the video please give it a
thumb up and consider subscribing to my
channel
[Music]